<html>
<body>
<div id='index'></div>
<div id='main'><h2>Summary</h2>
<p>This scenarios examines how the <ref name="risk" />s should be managed on a construction site.</p>
<p>This involves both keeping track of the existing <ref name="risk" />s as well as inspecting the site
for the new <ref name="risk" />s, checking the state of the installations <em>etc.</em></p>
<h2>Models</h2>
<model name="standard/risk_level">
<p>Risk levels defined at the national and international level.</p>
</model>
<model name="risks">
<p>This model captures all the <ref name="risk" />s.</p>
<p>As <ref name="risk" /> is a non-IFC entity, it does not live in
<modelref name="evolving_plan#bim_extended" />.</p>
</model>
<h2>Definitions</h2>
<def name="risk_manager">
<p><level name="site">This is an <ref name="actor_management#role" /> that manages certain kinds
of <ref name="risk" />s.</level></p>
<p>For example, this can be a health &amp; safety manager monitoring the fall risks or
site protection manager monitoring the fire risks, but can also be a
construction engineer responsible for curing the concrete <em>etc.</em></p>
</def>
<def name="preventive_resource">
<p><level name="zone">This is an <ref name="actor_management#role" /> that is responsible for
one or more <ref name="responsibility_zone" />s on the construction site to keep track and mitigate
the <ref name="risk" />s.</level></p>
<p>(Mind that a preventive resource and the <ref name="risk_manager" /> can be one and the same
person in certain sites, <em>e.g.</em>, when the site is small.)</p>
</def>
<def name="responsibility_zone">
<p>A responsibility zone as an <code>IfcZone</code> living in the <modelref name="evolving_plan#bim_extended"/>.</p>
</def>
<def name="assignment">
<p>Responsibility assignment of a <ref name="preventive_resource" />.</p>
<p>The assignment is a non-IFC data structure and relates the <ref name="risk" />s and
the <ref name="preventive_resource" />s.</p>
</def>
<def name="risk_level">
<p>This is the risk level according to different standards.</p>
<p>The risk level refers to a concrete standard in <modelref name="standard/risk_level" />.</p>
</def>
<def name="risk_zone">
<p>This is an <code>IfcZone</code> living in <modelref name="evolving_plan#bim_extended" /> that demarcates a zone
of a specific <ref name="risk" />.</p>
</def>
<def name="risk_type">
<p>The risk type is a more general type of a risk (&quot;fall&quot;, &quot;fire&quot; <em>etc.</em>).</p>
</def>
<def name="risk">
<p>A risk is a custom, non-IFC entity representing a safety or an economic risk.</p>
<p>A risk is of a <ref name="risk_type" />.</p>
<p>It is tied to zero, one or multiple <ref name="responsibility_zone"/>s.</p>
<p>The risk can be associated with zero, one or multiple <ref name="risk_zone" />s.
If there are no <ref name="risk_zone" />s defined, the risk is considered unconfined.
If there is one or more <ref name="risk_zone" />s defined, the risk applies only to these zones.</p>
<p>The risk is also associated with zero, one or more <ref name="scheduling#task" />s. </p>
<p>The risk must have a validity time span (which can also be open-ended).
There should be a special flag to indicate that the temporal validity of a risk is directly
tied to its corresponding <ref name="scheduling#task" />s.
For example, this is important if the <ref name="scheduling#task" />s are re-scheduled and the risk
temporal validity needs to reflect that.</p>
<p>The risk is assigned a <ref name="risk_level" />.</p>
<p>The risk can be related to one or multiple <ref name="topic_management#topic" />s (<em>e.g.</em>,
when a safety-relevant element is missing or damaged).</p>
<p>The risk lives in <modelref name="risks" />s and have
<ref name="unique_resource_identification#identifier" />.</p>
</def>
<h2>Scenario</h2>
<p>In this scenario, we look into how to manage the <ref name="risk" />s with the system.</p>
<p>The <ref name="risk" /> in the context of this scenario does not refer strictly to a safety
risk (such as fall risk or fire risk), but encompasses a much broader family of risks (such as
concrete cracking, which is an economic risk, but not necessarily a safety risk).</p>
<h3>As-planned</h3>
<p><level name="office">We assume that the data from <modelref name="evolving_plan#bim3d" /> and
<modelref name="evolving_plan#bim_extended" /> is accessible from the office.</level></p>
<p><strong>Specification of the <ref name="risk" />s</strong>.
There should be an application so that the <ref name="risk_manager" /> can easily convert
a <ref name="scheduling#task" /> to a <ref name="risk" /> and capture the additional
information such as the <ref name="risk_zone" />.</p>
<p>There should be also a <ref name="risk" /> management application so that
the <ref name="risk_manager" /> can also create, list and modify the <ref name="risk" />s (
together with the <ref name="risk_zone" />s, time span <em>etc.</em>).</p>
<p>Mind that a <ref name="risk" /> needs not be necessarily associated with a
<ref name="scheduling#task" />.</p>
<p><phase name="planning">The <ref name="risk_manager"/> inputs the initial set of
<ref name="risk"/>s already known during the planning.</phase></p>
<p><phase name="construction">Both the <ref name="risk_manager"/> and
the <ref name="preventive_resource"/> can insert new and change existing
<ref name="risk"/>s accordingly.</phase></p>
<p><strong>Specification of the <ref name="assignment" />s</strong>.
There needs to be a separate application so that the <ref name="risk_manager" /> can create, list
and modify <ref name="assignment" />s of the <ref name="risk" />s to
the <ref name="preventive_resource" />s.</p>
<p>Though some <ref name="risk" />s are not necessarily spatially confined
(<em>e.g.</em>, some risks can be abstract, such as &quot;the workers are wearing safety helmets&quot;),
they are still part of an <ref name="assignment" />.
In these cases, the <ref name="assignment" /> means that a <ref name="preventive_resource" /> is
responsible for the unconfined <ref name="risk" /> in the given zone (<em>e.g</em>, that all workers wear a
helmet in the given zone).</p>
<h3>As-observed</h3>
<p>The <ref name="risk_manager" /> needs to create <ref name="uxv_recording#focus_spot" />s in order
to observe the necessary spots for potential new or changed risks.</p>
<p>The <ref name="uxv_recording#focus_spot" />s are observable through
<ref name="digital_reconstruction#recording" />s and taken into account during the
<ref name="uxv_recording#mission" />s.</p>
<h3>Divergence</h3>
<p>Depending on the <ref name="risk" />, we can use <scenarioref name="thermal_inspection" /> and/or
<scenarioref name="virtual_inspection" /> to inspect whether the risk is present or absent.</p>
<p>For example, the <ref name="preventive_resource" /> can check if the safety nets are still there and
not damaged using <scenarioref name="virtual_inspection" />.
The absent, ill-placed or damaged elements are reported as a
<ref name="topic_management#topic" /> using <scenarioref name="topic_management" />.</p>
<p>This is different to assessing or discovering a new risk (please see the
<a href="#section-Safety">Safety section</a>).</p>
<h3>Analytics</h3>
<p>The system allows the <ref name="risk_manager" /> to track the following indicators:</p>
<ul>
<li>Number of <ref name="topic_management#topic" />s related to escalated <ref name="risk" />s of a
certain <ref name="risk_type" /> (<em>e.g.</em>, as a pre-defined <ref name="topic_management#label" />).</li>
</ul>
<p>The <ref name="assignment" />s should be visualized separately (<em>e.g.</em>, as a 3D or 2D geometry).</p>
<h3>Scheduling</h3>
<p>The <ref name="risk_manager" /> needs to inspect the <ref name="scheduling#task" />s
in <scenarioref name="scheduling" /> as the <ref name="scheduling#task_shadow" />s are
linked to the <ref name="risk" />s.</p>
<h3>Safety</h3>
<p><strong>Virtual inspection.</strong>
The <ref name="risk_manager" /> filters the <ref name="scheduling#task" />s with
an elevated risk in <scenarioref name="virtual_inspection" />.</p>
<p>The spatial and temporal relations between the <ref name="risk_zone" />s are then automatically
visualized in <scenarioref name="virtual_inspection" /> (<em>e.g.</em>, using the temporal validity
of the <ref name="risk" />).</p>
<p><strong>Reporting.</strong>
The system needs to report an overview of all the <ref name="risk" />s.</p>
<p>The <ref name="risk" />s need to be displayed together with their  related
<ref name="scheduling#task" />s, if any, as a time table.</p>
<p>For example, we can display the <ref name="risk" />s as a Gantt diagram.
The <ref name="risk" />s would be represented with thick bars, while the related
<ref name="scheduling#task" />s would be visualized inside these bigger bars as thin bars.
(Mind that this is just an idea and needs to be experimented with during the implementation.)</p>
<p>The user should filter by:</p>
<ul>
<li><ref name="risk_type" /> (<em>e.g.</em>, show only fire risks),</li>
<li>time range, and</li>
<li>spatially (by a bounding box, super-zones <em>etc.</em>; the spatial filtering takes
<ref name="risk_zone" />s into account; there should be a special flag to include/exclude
unconfined <ref name="risk_zone" />s).</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Escalation.</strong>
If there is a problematic <ref name="scheduling#task" />,
the <ref name="risk_manager" /> should create a <ref name="topic_management#topic" />.</p>
<h2>Test Cases</h2>
<test name="test_for_magnitude">
<p>We write a script to generate automatically dummy tasks.</p>
<p>We also use generated images from <testref name="thermal_inspection#test_for_magnitude" />
to randomly assign them to the dummy tasks.</p>
</test>
<test name="blind_test_removed_item">
<p>(This is a blind experiment and might not be legally possible.)</p>
<p>Remove a safety item and inform the workers.</p>
<p>Check that the responsible person could find out that it is missing using the system. </p>
</test> 
<test name="analytics_correct_on_an_example">
<p>Record 3 complete states of the whole system and freeze them. </p>
<p>Manually compute the expected analytics. </p>
<p>Check that the output of the system coincides with the manually computed analytics.</p>
</test>
<h2>Acceptance Criteria</h2>
<acceptance name="magnitude">
<p>The system needs to handle the risk related <ref name="scheduling#task" />s in the
order of thousands.</p>
</acceptance>
</div>
</body>
</html>