<html>
<body>
<div id='index'></div>
<div id='main'><h2>Summary</h2>
<p>This scenario examines how we can uniquely identify the instances of all the entities in our system.</p>
<h2>Models</h2>
<p><em>Intentionally left empty.</em></p>
<h2>Definitions</h2>
<def name="identifier" >
<p>From <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_Resource_Identifier">Wikipedia</a>:</p>
<p>A Uniform Resource Identifier (URI) is a unique identifier used by web technologies.
URIs may be used to identify anything, including real-world objects, such as people and places,
concepts, or information resources such web pages and books.</p>
</def>
<h2>Scenario</h2>
<p>Our system supports many non-IFC entities (such as <ref name="risk_management#risk" /> and
<ref name="on-site_logistics#delivery_update" />).</p>
<p>Since we shadow these entities as references in BIM through
<ref name="evolving_plan#non_ifc_entity" />, they need an <ref name="identifier" />.</p>
<p>We propose the following schema for identification:</p>
<pre><code>bimprove://{entity}/{identifier}
</code></pre>
<p>The <code>identifier</code> in the <ref name="identifier" /> does not have to match the
<ref name="evolving_plan#guid" />. This is important as one part of the system might
not control the other part (or a dependency) so it can not control the identification conflicts.</p>
<p>Here are a couple examples of the <ref name="identifier" />:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>bimprove://risk/123e4567-e89b-12d3-a456-426614174000</code> </li>
<li><code>bimprove://delivery/d67e5a7d-a77c-44bd-b8f7-b860b370c4db</code></li>
</ul>
<p>For example, the fall risk with URI <code>bimprove://risk/123e4567-e89b-12d3-a456-426614174000</code>
can be shadowed by <code>IfcExternalReference</code> in <modelref name="evolving_plan#bim_extended" />
with a <ref name="evolving_plan#guid" /> set to <code>52a844ac-3f37-456c-9e86-9e1b905600a7</code>. </p>
<p><strong>Abstraction</strong>.
We abstract the links to these entities from the storage. </p>
<p>For example, the fall risk might have an REST API accessible through a URL
<code>http://some-server.com/risk/123e4567-e89b-12d3-a456-426614174000</code>.
However, it could also provide a GraphQL interface, direct SQL interface
(<em>e.g.</em>, <code>sql://risk/123e4567-e89b-12d3-a456-426614174000</code>) or some other interface.</p>
<p>We consider this to be an implementation detail so that we intentionally decouple how the backend
retrieves or modifies the information about the entity from its identification.</p>
<p><strong>Recordings</strong>.
The <ref name="digital_reconstruction#recording" /> needs to specify the source and the sensor and
the accuracy of the sensor:</p>
<pre><code>recording://{type of the device}/{identifier of the device}/{identifier of the sensor of the device}/{identifier of the recording}
</code></pre>
<p>Examples:</p>
<pre><code>recording://uxv/ruprechts-uav-3/photo-odometry/7f0d4cad-4a22-4a6d-8f00-10ca08d3e4d4
</code></pre>
<pre><code>recording://manual/some-body/smartphone-camera/89dd9240-d11d-4f79-a7e1-0fe9a5af4d46
</code></pre>
<p>(Note that we still need to figure this out.
This is just a first sketch of how we could identify the
<ref name="digital_reconstruction#recording" />s.)</p>
<p><em>The remaining sections intentionally left empty.</em></p>
</div>
</body>
</html>